<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Tutorial :: Cantara</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/tutorial/index.html</link><description>The following pages will give you a detailed instruction to Cantara and how the software works. For most users, Cantara should work well out of the box. However, if there are problems or issues which can’t be solved, feel also free to go to the Github repository and ask for additional help.
Info Please note that this tutorial is for version 2.5.0 and later. Prior versions won’t support all the features which are described in this section.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 15:37:14 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cantara.app/tutorial/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Cantara Works</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/tutorial/how-cantara-works/index.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 15:37:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.cantara.app/tutorial/how-cantara-works/index.html</guid><description>Background Story When I was at my high school time, I became part in the leadership of a Christian youth group. When conducting our events, we liked to sing a few songs at the beginning. However the problem occurred that the available song books where not enough and the content was sometimes not matching with the songs which were wished. At that time I was looking for an available song presentation program and became disappointed quickly.</description></item><item><title>Install Cantara</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/tutorial/install-cantara/index.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 15:37:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.cantara.app/tutorial/install-cantara/index.html</guid><description>This page describes how you can install Cantara on your local operating system.
Windows Installation on Windows is very easy and done in just one minute. You can either use the Windows package manager Winget or download and run the installer manually.
Using winget (Windows 10 and Windows 11) If you are running one of the modern versions of Windows (Windows 10 1709 or later), you can use Winget to install Cantara safely and keep it up to date.</description></item><item><title>General Usage</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/tutorial/how-to-use-it/index.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 15:37:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.cantara.app/tutorial/how-to-use-it/index.html</guid><description>First Steps After the installation, simply open Cantara with your start menu or the cantara command. You will then see the welcome assistent which helps you to go through the configuration of Cantara. Here you should choose a song repository directory where you all the song lyrics files are stored. If you have none yet, you can create an empty new folder and select it as your song repository. The assistent will suggest you to add “Amazing Grace” as an example song which you can use to understand how the program works.</description></item><item><title>Manage Songs</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/tutorial/where-to-get-the-songs/index.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 15:37:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.cantara.app/tutorial/where-to-get-the-songs/index.html</guid><description>When using Cantara, you will need to collect, edit and distribute songs which can be used for presenting or exporting. If you start Cantara for the first time, you will notice that–depending on what you have chosen in the welcome assistent–you might only find one song available: “Amazing Grace”. From that point on, you can start to get and add songs.
The folder which you choose two be your song repository will contain all the songs which you use in Cantara.</description></item><item><title>Song Meta Data</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/tutorial/meta-data/index.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 15:37:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.cantara.app/tutorial/meta-data/index.html</guid><description>Cantara allows you to fetch and display meta data from the songs. Depending on the song format, Cantara will get the following meta data.
CCLI Songselect Following data will be collected from each CCLI songselect lyrics file:
author: The name(s) of all author(s) separated by a ‘|’. ccli-licensenumber: The number of the CCLI license which is dependent on the user account (not on the song) ccli-songnumber: The CCLI number on the song which is dependent on the song.</description></item></channel></rss>