<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cantara Song</title><link>https://reckel-jm.github.io/cantara-song/</link><description>Recent content on Cantara Song</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 22:27:39 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://reckel-jm.github.io/cantara-song/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How Cantara Works</title><link>https://reckel-jm.github.io/cantara-song/tutorial/how-cantara-works/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 15:37:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://reckel-jm.github.io/cantara-song/tutorial/how-cantara-works/</guid><description>Background Story When I was at my high school time, I became part in the leadership of a Christian youth group. When conducting our events, we liked to sing a few songs at the beginning. However the problem occured that the available song books where not enough and the content was sometimes not matching with the songs which were wished. At that time I was looking for an available song presentation program and became dissapointed quickly.</description></item><item><title>Install Cantara</title><link>https://reckel-jm.github.io/cantara-song/tutorial/install-cantara/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 15:37:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://reckel-jm.github.io/cantara-song/tutorial/install-cantara/</guid><description>Installing Cantara is quite simple if you are using Windows or Linux. It should also be no problem with Mac OS. Here you will find a detailed description for your operating system.
For Support of the CCLI Songselect file format, please download the Version 2.3 Beta. You can find the source code and binaries on Github.
Windows The installation using windows is very easy. There is an installer which you can use and which will lead you through the process.</description></item><item><title>How to use it</title><link>https://reckel-jm.github.io/cantara-song/tutorial/how-to-use-it/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 15:37:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://reckel-jm.github.io/cantara-song/tutorial/how-to-use-it/</guid><description>First Steps After the installation, simply open Cantara with your start menu or the cantara command. You will then be asked to choose a directory for the song repository. Here you should choose a song repository directory where you all the song lyrics files are stored. If you have none yet, you can use the three points &amp;hellip; at the right size of the edit field to open a folder browser.</description></item><item><title>Where to get the songs</title><link>https://reckel-jm.github.io/cantara-song/tutorial/where-to-get-the-songs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 15:37:14 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://reckel-jm.github.io/cantara-song/tutorial/where-to-get-the-songs/</guid><description>Getting the songs might be one of the most important questions when using a song presentation software. Cantara supports two different song formats. One has the file ending .song and is very simple for it just contains the lyrics in the order as they should be presented. The other format is used by CCLI Songselect and has the file endings .txt or .ccli. CCLI is a commercial database where you can download a lot of Christian songs for the use in churches or Christian groups.</description></item></channel></rss>