<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cantara</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/index.html</link><description>Welcome to this webpage!
Cantara is a song presentation software which can be used for presenting songs in churches, small groups or karaoke parties. It supports various input formats and can create beautiful presentation slides or export the presentation to various output formats (pictures, pptx, WhatsApp message and a lot more) so that they can be used for a variety of purposes. Cantara has the following advantages:
Super-fast and lightweight: Cantara is less then 10 MB of size and uses the components available on the local operation system as far as possible.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 16:08:51 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cantara.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Release Notes</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/releasenotes/index.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 16:34:40 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.cantara.app/releasenotes/index.html</guid><description>This page contains information about the changes in different versions (releases) and plans for the future.
Releases Version 2.6.0 (2024-05-31) Migrate to bgrabitmap for better handling and displaying of the presentation slides. In the future, further text effects like shadows etc. can be easily implemented. Redesign the multi screen presentation controller: In addition to the songs, every slide with content is listed and can be selected directly. Context menu of presentation window: Fullscreen and ending of presentation is now also selectable with that menu.</description></item><item><title>Quick Start</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/quick-start/index.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 11:04:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.cantara.app/quick-start/index.html</guid><description>Starting with Cantara is very easy and can be done while following this three steps:
Download Cantara Collect Songs Run and configure Cantara While a detailed explanation with download links can be found in the Tutorial Section, this page just contains some short advises.
Download Cantara There are several download links for different operation systems.
Go to the Download and Installation Tutorial Section for further information. Check out the Releases Page on Github for further options.</description></item><item><title>Tutorial</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/tutorial/index.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 15:24:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.cantara.app/tutorial/index.html</guid><description>The following pages will give you a detailed instruction to Cantara and how the software works. For most users, Cantara should work well out of the box. However, if there are problems or issues which can’t be solved, feel also free to go to the Github repository and ask for additional help.
Info Please note that this tutorial is for version 2.5.0 and later. Prior versions won’t support all the features which are described in this section.</description></item><item><title>Get Help</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/get-help/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 14:58:43 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.cantara.app/get-help/index.html</guid><description>Cantara is a volunteer project and therefore offers no professional support. However, the developer is very happy to help if there are any questions or troubles. The preferred way of contact would be to open a GitHub issue.
GitHub is a free software collaboration platform. You can easily create an account there and then open an issue with your question or the problem which you have.</description></item><item><title>Contribute</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/contribute/index.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 18:41:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.cantara.app/contribute/index.html</guid><description>Cantara is free Software and has been developed with a lot of patience and passion. If you like it, I would be grateful if you consider one of the things below. Thank you for using Cantara. It is my pleasure and honor!
Give feedback, recommendations and bug reports If you find any issues, have ideas or recommendations or want to report a bug, please open an issue at the Cantara Github repository.</description></item><item><title>Blog</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/blog/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 16:08:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.cantara.app/blog/index.html</guid><description>In this section, some articles about Cantara will get published from time to time.
Published Artcles February 2nd: The General Roadmap of the Project</description></item><item><title>Imprint and Data Privacy</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/imprint/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 15:39:43 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.cantara.app/imprint/index.html</guid><description>Imprint This site is run by:
Jan Martin Reckel
Jollystraße 73 76137 Karlsruhe
Use GitHub for any software related contact request.
The content of this webpage is provided as it is without any warranty or assurance that the information might be correct. The author takes no responsibility for external links or references.
Data Privacy For this Webpage This webpage has no contact form or any function implemented which would save or track user data.</description></item></channel></rss>