<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cantara</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/index.html</link><description>A program for quick, easy but beautiful hymn presenting in churches. Welcome to this webpage! Cantara is an open source software which is used for managing and presenting hymns and songs in churches, small groups and more. It supports various input formats and can create beautiful presentation slides or export the presentation to various output formats (pictures, pptx, WhatsApp message and a lot more) so that they can be used for a variety of purposes.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 16:08:51 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://www.cantara.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Release Notes</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/releasenotes/index.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2022 16:34:40 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.cantara.app/releasenotes/index.html</guid><description>This page contains information about the changes in different versions (releases) and plans for the future.
Releases Version 2.7.0 (2026-02-21) New Features Per-song style overrides: Each song in the selection can now have its own background image, background colour, text colour, font, transparency, and horizontal alignment — independent of the global presentation settings. A dedicated “Song Style” dialog is accessible via the right-click context menu on any song. Per-song PPTX masters: When exporting to PowerPoint, each song can use its own custom master slide. Fade transition between slides: A smooth cross-fade effect between slides can be enabled in the settings. The fade duration is configurable (default: 150 ms). Black screen on empty slide: A new setting causes Cantara to show a pure black screen instead of the background when an empty slide is displayed. JSON song selection export/import: Song selections can now be saved and loaded as .json files. The format bundles song content, per-song style overrides, and background images into a single portable file, enabling full round-trip export/import across machines. Windows dark mode: Cantara now follows the system dark mode setting on Windows. Windows installer: An Inno Setup installer is now available for Windows. Third-party libraries dialog: A new dialog lists all third-party libraries used by Cantara along with their licences. Improvements Improved Flatpak permissions handling: Cantara now uses the XDG portal for file access in sandboxed environments and provides a standard open dialog for selecting background images. Improved text rendering with a custom word-wrap function for more accurate line breaking. Improved font rendering quality settings. Updated and extended translations. The main window title has been simplified to “Cantara”. Bug Fixes Fixed a crash (SIGSEGV) when starting a presentation after songs were added via “Select All” or drag-and-drop, or after using the search filter — the TRepoFile object reference was not attached to list entries in those code paths. Fixed the song editor not opening the correct song when invoked from the context menu (wrong file lookup and a form initialisation timing issue). Fixed background colour and transparency changes not being reflected in the song style preview dialog. Fixed background colour and transparency changes not being applied in the presentation window and image export when two songs share the same background image but use different colours. Fixed metadata parsing truncating field values that contained a colon character. Fixed a layout overlap of the background colour panel and an incorrect sign on the transparency value in the song style dialog. Fixed a type cast error in the PPTX custom master slide lookup. Fixed an exception when closing the application under certain conditions. Fixed .txt files not being recognised as valid song files. Fixed several text sizing and line-length calculation issues in the presentation canvas. Fixed a content-area layout bug affecting Cantara running as a Flatpak. Version 2.6.0 (2024-05-31) Migrate to bgrabitmap for better handling and displaying of the presentation slides. In the future, further text effects like shadows etc. can be easily implemented. Redesign the multi screen presentation controller: In addition to the songs, every slide with content is listed and can be selected directly. Context menu of presentation window: Fullscreen and ending of presentation is now also selectable with that menu. Minor improvements of the song editor and full text search. Add “Select all Songs” under File menu in song selection. Bugfix: Wrong display of presentation when no specific font has been selected #24 Bugfix: Drag and Drop exception in song selection window Bugfix: Wrong escaping of special characters in pptx-export A lot of minor bugfixes and corrections Translation update Version 2.5.0 (2023-08-21) Complete rewriting of large parts of the source code including the internal structures for generating and painting presentation slides Improvement of the presentation layout Improvement of the song editor Implementation of a preview of the presentation in the settings menu Implementation of slide export to pptx (using PptxgenJs) Implementation of slide export to pictures Implementation of song lyrics export to markup text files Implementation of a full text search for browsing song lyrics Implementation of a two language song presentation Improvements of the presentation window and control (more keys and remote controls are supported) Fix issue #17 Cantara can now be directly opened with a .songtex-file. Version 2.4.1 (2023-01-30) Italian and Spanish translation The version 2.4.1. adds Italian and Spanish translation to Cantara. Despite that, there is no additional functionality compared to Version 2.4.0 which means that if you are not using one of the languages, you don’t necessarily need to update to this version.</description></item><item><title>Quick Start</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/quick-start/index.html</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 11:04:06 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.cantara.app/quick-start/index.html</guid><description>Starting with Cantara is very easy and can be done while following this three steps:
Download Cantara Collect Songs Run and configure Cantara While a detailed explanation with download links can be found in the Tutorial Section, this page just contains some short advises.
Download Cantara There are several download links for different operation systems.
Go to the Download and Installation Tutorial Section for further information. Check out the Releases Page on Github for further options. Collect Songs Use services like CCLI Song Select or other databases to get lyrics for the songs which you want to sing! You don’t know where to start? Take a look here.</description></item><item><title>Tutorial</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/tutorial/index.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 15:24:31 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.cantara.app/tutorial/index.html</guid><description>The following pages will give you a detailed instruction to Cantara and how the software works. For most users, Cantara should work well out of the box. However, if there are problems or issues which can’t be solved, feel also free to go to the Github repository and ask for additional help.
Info Please note that this tutorial is for version 2.5.0 and later. Prior versions won’t support all the features which are described in this section.</description></item><item><title>Get Help</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/get-help/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 14:58:43 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.cantara.app/get-help/index.html</guid><description>Cantara is a volunteer project and therefore offers no professional support. However, the developer is very happy to help if there are any questions or troubles. The preferred way of contact would be to open a GitHub issue.
GitHub is a free software collaboration platform. You can easily create an account there and then open an issue with your question or the problem which you have.</description></item><item><title>Contribute</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/contribute/index.html</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 18:41:23 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.cantara.app/contribute/index.html</guid><description>Cantara is free Software and has been developed with a lot of patience and passion. If you like it, I would be grateful if you consider one of the things below. Thank you for using Cantara. It is my pleasure and honor!
Give feedback, recommendations and bug reports If you find any issues, have ideas or recommendations or want to report a bug, please open an issue at the Cantara Github repository. I work completely via Github on the project, so that would be the best way to go. If you have no Github account and don’t want to create one, ask a friend to do it for you.</description></item><item><title>Blog</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/blog/index.html</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 16:08:51 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://www.cantara.app/blog/index.html</guid><description>In this section, some articles about Cantara will get published from time to time.
Published Artcles February 2nd: The General Roadmap of the Project</description></item><item><title>Imprint and Data Privacy</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/imprint/index.html</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Aug 2022 15:39:43 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://www.cantara.app/imprint/index.html</guid><description>Imprint This site is run privately by:
Jan Martin Reckel
Use GitHub for any software related contact request.
The content of this webpage is provided as it is without any warranty or assurance that the information might be correct. The author takes no responsibility for external links or references.
Data Privacy For this Webpage This webpage has no contact form or any function implemented which would save or track user data. No analytic tools are used. The webpage provider does not set any cookies.</description></item></channel></rss>