<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Release Notes :: Cantara</title><link>https://www.cantara.app/releasenotes/index.html</link><description>This page contains information about the changes in different versions (releases) and plans for the future.
Releases Version 2.6.0 (2024-05-31) Migrate to bgrabitmap for better handling and displaying of the presentation slides. In the future, further text effects like shadows etc. can be easily implemented. Redesign the multi screen presentation controller: In addition to the songs, every slide with content is listed and can be selected directly. Context menu of presentation window: Fullscreen and ending of presentation is now also selectable with that menu. Minor improvements of the song editor and full text search. Add “Select all Songs” under File menu in song selection. Bugfix: Wrong display of presentation when no specific font has been selected #24 Bugfix: Drag and Drop exception in song selection window Bugfix: Wrong escaping of special characters in pptx-export A lot of minor bugfixes and corrections Translation update Version 2.5.0 (2023-08-21) Complete rewriting of large parts of the source code including the internal structures for generating and painting presentation slides Improvement of the presentation layout Improvement of the song editor Implementation of a preview of the presentation in the settings menu Implementation of slide export to pptx (using PptxgenJs) Implementation of slide export to pictures Implementation of song lyrics export to markup text files Implementation of a full text search for browsing song lyrics Implementation of a two language song presentation Improvements of the presentation window and control (more keys and remote controls are supported) Fix issue #17 Cantara can now be directly opened with a .songtex-file. Version 2.4.1 (2023-01-30) Italian and Spanish translation The version 2.4.1. adds Italian and Spanish translation to Cantara. Despite that, there is no additional functionality compared to Version 2.4.0 which means that if you are not using one of the languages, you don’t necessarily need to update to this version.</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate/><atom:link href="https://www.cantara.app/releasenotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/></channel></rss>